Elías Vitaliano Vidaurre Dávila

| Phone: +52 1 33.14.08.10.05 dj.vita.09@gmail.com | Github: https://github.com/djvita/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/vitavidaurre

Personal Statement

I am a hardworking, dedicated person, who loves a challenge and is always looking for "the next big thing"; who wants to become a better person learning new skills. I have a good memory, I make decisions quickly to solve my personal, school and work problems. And I love challenges.

Key Skills

Problem solving Results Focus Team work, Independence Professionalism Customer Service Sociability Creativity Multitask

Leadership Analysis Constant Improvement Experimentation Project-building Working under pressure and with a deadline

Tolerance Positive Attitude Automating Menial / Repetitive Tasks and Tests Think outside the box Patience

Language Skills

English and Spanish 100% Fluently spoken, written, read and thought out, TOEFL 617; French 20%

Technical Skills

Click here to view my github repos

Programming Languages – note never developed code professionally!

Intermediate (1 years)	Basic (understands code)	Familiar with (read api, one demo etc.)
Python SQL Bash Linux CURL REST APIs	Java/C#, Obj-C/Swift, HTML/CSS Javascript, C/C++	PHP, Javascript/JQuery/Dojo/Ajax/Node, XML, Ruby/Ruby on Rails
CURL REST APIS	C/C++	Rdiis

Programs

Intermediate (2 years)	Beginner (1-2 years)	Familiar with (read api, one demo etc.)
Office, Browsers, VIM, IDE's, IPython	SQL Server, Arduino, PLC Step 7, Android	HP ALM, Selenium, Kali Linux Libraries,

Tools/APIs

· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·		
Intermediate (1 years)	Basic	Familiar with (read api, one demo etc.)
Git, Heroku Postman	Docker, Virtualbox, VMWare, Vagrant	REST OpenCV, NLTK, requests, Twitter/FB/Dropbox/Google APIs

Operating Systems

Windows 7-11, OSX, Linux/Unix (Ubuntu, RedHat, Kali) All 3 Used day by day.

Engineering and Software Development

Data Science, Machine Learning, Cloud, Big Data, Testing, Ecommerce, Security, ITIL, PMP, Agile, Design Patterns, Test Automation

Work Experience

Brightcove, Tier 2 Technical Support

May 2019 to Present

Providing technical support to Brightcove's customers, in nearly all products including:

Web player front end development, CMS management, CDN support, SSO IDP security, Live streaming with HLS/RTMP via encoder, REST API with postman, managing accounts.

Curriculum Vitae

Elías Vitaliano Vidaurre Dávila

Solving the customer's problems with web publishing, playback, CDN auth, user/video management, ingesting content, transcoding content, live event support in real time. Brightcove is CISA certified and has strict KPI's including customer satisfaction. Providind top-notch service and triaging bugs to development teams and third party partners. Troubleshooting issues and providing solutions. To developers, providing a sample page with a test case reproducing the issue. Narrowing down the complexity of front end publishing and live streaming to customers that have not technical background, keeping them happy.

Oracle, Technical Consultant, Tier 2 Cloud and Big Data Support

August 2015 to 2019, Support Technitian to Sales teams for Big Data, IaaS, PaaS, Middleware, IoT and SaaS HCM. Process level 2 Tickets on bugs/errors/outages on Cloud and On-premise Environments lent to the Oracle Sales Team to sell. Troubleshoot Production products with development/product management, sales/ pre-sales and cloud support. Refresh, Archive and Restore environments. Test new Product Releases, help automate repeated tasks such as password resets, user creation and tenant provisioning. Assist with development of demos that salepeople use to sell to outside customers. Support, Cloud, Big Data, PaaS, IaaS, IoT, Support, Level 2, Cloudera, Sales.

HITSS, IBM Contractor for Test Engineer and Software Developer

November 2014 to July 2015, moved to Internet Technologies to Knowledge Anyhow Workbench. Testing the Full stack, Demos, Fixing small defects, investigating libraries, competitor's products. Data Science, Python, iPthon, Machine Learning, scitkit-learn, Data Mining, pandas, matplotlib, octave, R, UI Testing, Development, Version control through gitlab, SCRUM, UI Design, Performance Testing, Dev Ops, Cloud Services.

(05/2014 to 10/2014) Testing Accessibility, Globalization, UI, Preformance and Usability for <u>BlueMix</u>. Project contract extended twice due to excellent results.

Softtek, Software Engineer

(04/2014 to 05/2014) Part of AMS (Applications Management Service), handling support tickets for clients such as HP, General Electric, Government agencies and Banks. Took only training before I got job offer for IBM Contractor. OOP, UML, SQL Server (ANSI), .NET (C#, ADO.NET, Console, Windows Forms, Services, Web, ASP.NET). Project Management (Risk, Configuration Management, Process Improvement, Six Sigma, Verification and Validation, Pugh Matrix, CMMI).

Continental Automotive (Intern Engineer)

(09/2013 to 02/2014) HECO2, a project to simulate the dash cover of the 2020's. Innovative project: the car will recognize a driver and calculate the most gas-economic trajectory saved through their driving behaviour. Using OpenGL ES2.0, Linux on ARM on an I.MX6, OpenCV, OpenNI, OpenFrameWorks, QT and Samba. Working in an Engineering team Documentation of Processes Testing and Software Development Working on a Linux Environment Embedded Systems and Performance Knowledge of Automotive Industry

Insight Demand Creation (Field Applications Engineer Intern)

(08/2013 to 12/2013) As part of the Internship Program, Working with Insight Demand Creation, helping them with various activities such as validation, testing, sales process, marketing and customer service. Working in a Sales/Engineering team, Meeting and Communicationg with Component Manufacturers, ODMs and OEM/Assemblers, Learning more about the Consumer Electronics´ Design and Distribution, Trainings, Manuals and Product Briefs, Learning specific information about Electonic Components and Technologies behind the Industry, Critical Thinking and Problem Solving

Education

Universidad Autonoma de Guadalajara (09/2014-01/2017) Master's in Web Technologies

ITESM Campus Guadalajara, Zapopan

(01/2009 to 12/2013) B.S. Graduate in Mechatronics Engineering

Curriculum Vitae

Elías Vitaliano Vidaurre Dávila

Preparatoria No 10, Zapopan

(08/2006 to 12/2008) High School Technical Career in Business Administration

Key Academic Accomplishments

- -Outstanding Score in CENEVAL EGEL Mechatronics Exam (National Standarized Test)
- -2-time winner of highest average in Mechatronics Generation (2009 and 2010)
- -600 Hours Community Service (480 required): Providing Classes to Low Income Families in an ITESM Center. Nominated for Outstanding Achievement
- -Working with Continental Automotive on a project to simulate the dash cover of the 2020's. Using OpenGL ES2.0, Linux on ARM on an IMX6, OpenCV, OpenNI, OpenFrameWorks, QT and Samba.
- -Certification with IBM on their IBM University Program
- -Leading a Career wide contest, build and design a robot to shoot balls in a ping pong tennis competition. 7th place.
- -Creating a server on Heroku using Ruby on Rails, Cucumber (behavior-driven Design) and PostgreSQL for an **IOS app** we created, source code: https://github.com/djvita/memorandum

Work availability:

Full-Time and Travel (US Tourist Visa, Eligible for TN and HB-1, Passport).